(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
みんなー、今日は遊びに来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for coming to visit today!
お誕生日になりましたよー！
It's my birthday!
誰かが捨ててしまった
Picking up the yesterday
昨日を拾い上げ
that someone threw away.
我武者羅に手を伸ばした
Thrusting the answer for which
答えを突き付けて
I recklessly reached out my hand.
何を手に入れても
No matter what I obtain,
満足することはない
I am never satisfied.
複雑に絡んだ
Escape from the gaps
心の隙間から逃げ出せ
in my intricately entangled heart.
そうさ Make Treasure
That's right, make treasure
錆びついた時のなかに
within the rusted time.
君の声を聞く
I hear your voice,
このまま届けたい
I want to deliver it just like this.
光のなか 君が待ってる
Because I believe that
そう信じてるから
you're waiting in the light.
今すぐに
Right now.
すべてを使い果たした
The future where I've used up
未来は擦り切れて
everything is worn out.
躊躇いがちに選んだ
Even the dreams I hesitantly chose
夢さえ軋み出す
begin to creak.
憂鬱な日常
I don't even escape
抜け出すことさえしない
the melancholy daily life.
そんな君の側で
I refuse to keep waiting
待ち続けてるのは御免だ
by your side like that.
だから Make Treasure
So make treasure
錆びついた鏡のなか
within the rusted mirror.
自分を探して
Searching for myself,
この手で掴みたい
I want to grab it with this hand.
どこにいても 君が待ってる
Because I believe that no matter
そう信じてるから
where you are, you're waiting.
今すぐに
Right now.
今日は新衣装のお披露目もありますよ！
Today there's also the unveiling of a new outfit!
最後まで盛り上がってってねー！
Let's get excited until the end!
何を手に入れても
No matter what I obtain,
満足することはない
I am never satisfied.
複雑に絡んだ
Escape from the gaps
心の隙間から逃げ出せ
in my intricately entangled heart.
そうさ Make Treasure
That's right, make treasure
錆びついた時のなかに
within the rusted time.
君の声を聞く
I hear your voice,
このまま届けたい
I want to deliver it just like this.
光のなか 君が待ってる
Because I believe that
そう信じてるから
you're waiting in the light.
だから Make Treasure
So make treasure
錆びついた鏡のなか
within the rusted mirror.
自分を探して
Searching for myself,
この手で掴みたい
I want to grab it with this hand.
どこにいても 君が待ってる
Because I believe that no matter
そう信じてるから
where you are, you're waiting.
今すぐに
Right now.
Vocal: ときのそら
Vocal: Tokino Sora
Sweet dream...
Story dream...
空を駆けて 未来へと
Soaring through the sky, towards the future
空にかける橋 作詞・作曲：奥井雅美
Sora ni Kakeru Hashi (Bridge to the Sky)
Lyrics/Composition: Masami Okui
そらちゃん、おめでとう！
Sora-chan, congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ぎゅっと手を取り合い
Firmly holding each other's hands
はしゃいでたあの場所も
Even that place where we were frolicking
今でも変わらない
Still remains the same even now
風の匂いがした
There was the scent of the wind
古の思い出
Ancient memories
穢れなき瞳たち
Innocent eyes
微かに呼び戻されて
Vaguely called back
交差する記憶
Intersecting memories
あぁ
Ah...
大地と
With the earth
太陽
And the sun
どんなときもすべてを抱きしめた
Embracing everything at all times
大切な君を
My precious you
守りたいよ今
I want to protect you now
涙こぼれたら
If tears should fall
そっと風になる
I will gently become the wind
ただ胸に閉ざした
Just closed in my heart
扉なら開けてほしい
If it's a door, I want you to open it
さぁ 飛び出して未来へと
Come now, let's leap out towards the future
憎み合う心と
Hearts that hate each other
愛し合う心を持って
And hearts that love each other
同じくらい誰かのこと
About someone else just as much
ずっと思っている
I'm always thinking
それは鏡の中
That is inside the mirror
映り込んだ自分が
Where my own reflection
二つの心を持って
Having two hearts
生きてるように
Seems to be living
あぁ
Ah...
出会えた
I met you
仲間は
My comrades
優しさにすべてを代えていく
Changing everything into kindness
大切な人を
My precious person
守りたいよ今
I want to protect you now
ずっと一人きり
Being all alone all this time
強いふりしてた
I was pretending to be strong
譲れない願い重ね合わせ
Combining our unyielding wishes
一緒にさぁ
Together, come now
新しい未来へと
Towards a new future
そらちゃん、改めておめでとう！
Sora-chan, congratulations once again!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
めちゃめちゃお祝いするよ、今日は！
I'm going to celebrate so much today!
本当に！？
Really!?
もしも暗闇に心囚われて
If my heart were captured by darkness
光求めてる誰かがいたなら
And if there was someone seeking the light
大切な君を
My precious you
守りたいよ今
I want to protect you now
この手差し出せる
I can reach out this hand
勇気を持ちたい
I want to have the courage
大きな力を与えられて
Being given a great power
今ならさぁ
If it's now, come
旅立てる未来へと
I can set off towards the future
あの空を駆けて未来へと
Soaring through that sky, towards the future
あ〜〜〜！
Ah~~~!
空にかける橋
Bridge to the Sky
はい、というわけで最初のゲストはめあちゃーん！
Alright, so our first guest is Mea-chan!
さあ、やって参りました！
Now, here I am!
世界の、め、あ！
The world's Me-a!
だー！そらちゃん！だー！
Tada! Sora-chan! Tada!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
いや、久しぶりだね、めっちゃ。
Wow, it's been a while, hasn't it?
いつぶりだって言うぐらい久しぶり。
So long that I can't even remember when was the last time.
いや、本当に。
Yeah, for real.
いや、今日はね、あ、ここにもありますが、
Well, today, as it says here too,
ときのそらお披露目生誕祭ということで来てもらいました。
it's the Tokino Sora Debut Anniversary & Birthday Celebration, so I've had you come here.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
いや、呼んでくれてありがとう。
No, thank you for inviting me.
ありがとう！嬉しい！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy! I'm so happy!
いや、ちょっとね、コメントくんも、
Well, it seems like the comments section
なんかちょっと昇天しちゃったみたいで...
has ascended a bit...
ちょ、ちょっとね。
Just a little bit.
あがっちゃったようですね。
Seems like it's overloaded.
あがっちゃったみたいなんですけど。
It seems it's gone up.
え、まずはね、1曲目は『Stellar Time』という曲で、
Um, first, the first song was 'Stellar Time,'
あ、超かっこいい曲で私、苦手なんですけど...
a really cool song that I'm actually not very good at, but...
かっこよかったー！
It was cool!
え、苦手なの？
Wait, you're not good at it?
本当に苦手。
I'm really not good at it.
え、めっちゃかっこよかったよ。
But you were really cool.
でも、それを頑張って歌ってみようと思って1曲目にしました。
But I wanted to try my best to sing it, so I made it the first song.
はい！
Yes!
そして次、『空にかける橋』はですね、
And then next, for 'Bridge to the Sky,'
めあちゃんが星のめあちゃん。
Mea-chan is the 'Star' Mea-chan.
そう。
That's right.
そして私も星のモチーフがあるということで...
And since I also have a star motif...
お互いね、こう空に関わるじゃないですか、星って。
We both have things related to the sky, right? Stars.
いや、そうそう。
Yeah, exactly.
だから、空になんかちなんだ感じの曲で、
So, I wanted to sing a song together
なおかつ希望に溢れてるような曲を一緒に歌いたいなと思って。
that's related to the sky and is full of hope.
おー！嬉しい！嬉しい！
Oh! I'm so happy! I'm so happy!
いや、なんかさ、あの、ちょっと私はね、先に聞いたんだけれども...
Well, you know, I heard it a bit earlier...
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
歌詞割りとかも、あ、そう、だから、こだわってくれて...
The line distribution and stuff, yeah, you were really particular about it...
そう、希望に満ちたところとか、
Yeah, the parts full of hope
未来へ向かう感じのところをどうしてもめあちゃんに歌ってほしくて...
and the parts that feel like they're heading towards the future, I really wanted Mea-chan to sing...
めあちゃんの歌詞割りを決めた後に、自分の歌詞割りを決めたっていう感じでした。
So I decided Mea-chan's lines first, and then decided my own.
あ、そうなの！？
Oh, really!?
めあちゃんにここ歌ってもらおうから先に決めました。
I decided first by thinking, 'I want Mea-chan to sing this part.'
聞きました！？皆さん！
Did you hear that!? Everyone!
皆さん聞きました！？
Did everyone hear that!?
聞きました、皆さん？
Did you hear, everyone?
エモ、って言われてる。
People are saying it's 'emo.'
嬉しい。うん。
I'm glad. Yeah.
あとね、あの、やっぱり同じビクターでね、出してるわけじゃないですか。
And also, you know, we're both releasing music under Victor, right?
イエス！ウィー・アー！
Yes! We are!
ウィー・アー！
We are!
ウィー・アー、ビクター！
We are, Victor!
というわけで一緒にね、歌いたかったんですよ、ずっと。
So I've wanted to sing together with you for a long time.
やっとだね！
Finally!
やっと！
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
せっかくのお誕生日だから呼んじゃった。ありがとう。
Since it's my birthday, I invited you. Thank you.
ありがとうございます。私にとってもご褒美です。
Thank you very much. This is a treat for me too.
そんなことないでしょ。ありがとう。
That's not true. Thank you.
あ、一緒に、あ、ポーズ撮ってみようよ。
Ah, let's, ah, try taking a pose together.
うふふ。
Ehehe.
あ、マイク、イエーイ、声が消えてった。
Ah, the mic, yay, my voice was fading out.
イエーイ！
Yay!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
嬉しいね。私も嬉しいよ。
It's nice. I'm happy too.
嬉しいしか言ってない今日。
I've only been saying 'I'm happy' today.
いいよ、全然。今度また一緒に何かやろうね。
That's fine. Let's do something together again sometime.
え、やろう！
Eh, let's!
聞きました、皆さん？
Did you hear that, everyone?
全部...
Everything...
全部聞きました？
Did you hear everything?
聞きました？
Did you hear?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや、こちらこそ本当にね、忙しい中、来てもら...
No, likewise, really, thank you for having me come in the middle of being busy...
なんか業務連絡みたいになってる。
It's like a business contact.
違う違う、そういうつもりじゃなかった。
No, no, I didn't mean it that way.
あ、よかった、失礼しました。
Oh, good, my apologies.
じゃあね、この後もね、たくさんね、
Well then, I'm sure you'll be
歌うんだと思うので、楽しみにしてます。
singing a lot more after this, so I'm looking forward to it.
頑張ります！新衣装もね。
I'll do my best! The new outfit too.
あ、もちろん。ありがとう。
Ah, of course. Thank you.
じゃあ、この後も頑張ってね。
Well, good luck with the rest.
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
めあちゃんでした！
That was Mea-chan!
またね！ありがとう！
See you! Thank you!
お水を飲みましょう。
Let's drink some water.
そして、ステージパワーアップなんです！見て！
And, the stage is powered up! Look!
春だから。春だから、桜だよね、やっぱり。春だから。
Because it's spring. Because it's spring, it's gotta be cherry blossoms. Because it's spring.
まあ、それ以外にも1曲目的な意味でも桜にしたかったっていうのはあるんですけど。
Well, besides that, I also wanted to have cherry blossoms because of the meaning behind the first song.
あと、ここに星があったりとか。
Also, there are stars here.
ここね。
Right here.
とか、なぜかヌンヌンが増えてるとか、
And, for some reason, there are more Nun-nuns,
ちょっとね、色んなバージョンアップがあるんですよ。
you know, there are various upgrades.
ぜひぜひそちらのステージも楽しみながら見てもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could enjoy watching while looking at those parts of the stage too.
楽しみだなと思います！
I'm really looking forward to it!
イエーイ！
Yay!
では、次の曲に行きましょうか。
Now, shall we move on to the next song?
次の曲、聞いてください。
Please listen to the next song.
シュガーソングとビターステップ。
Sugar Song and Bitter Step.
シュガーソングとビターステップ
Sugar Song and Bitter Step
作詞・作曲：田淵智也
Lyrics/Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
レオナだぞー！
It's Reona!
来ちゃいました！
I've come!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
I've grown used to the uproar of these cataclysmic changes
こんな地表は平和と見まがう
On this surface that could be mistaken for peace
ランブリングコースター 揺さぶられながら
As I'm shaken by this rumbling coaster
見失えないものは何だ
What is the thing I cannot lose sight of?
平等性原理主義の概念に飲まれて
Swallowed by the concept of egalitarian fundamentalism
心までがまるでエトセトラ
Even my heart is like an et cetera
大嫌い 大好き ちゃんと喋らなきゃ
I hate it, I love it; if I don't speak up properly
人形とさして変わらないし
I'm no different from a doll
ああ 夜の街をゆく人だかりは
Ah, the crowds walking through the city at night
嬉しそうだったり 寂しそうだったり
Seem happy, or seem lonely
コントラストが五線譜を飛び回り
The contrast flies around the musical staff
歌とリズムになる
Becoming a song and a rhythm
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
It's so sweet and bitter, I feel like my head is spinning
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's keep the party going towards the south-southwest
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It'll be a night that surprises the whole world
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, reflecting in a chain reaction
蓋然性合理主義の正義に飲まれて
Swallowed by the justice of probabilistic rationalism
僕らの足はどっかへなりさがる
Our feet are dragging somewhere
こっちを向いてよ 背を向けないでよ
Look this way, don't turn your back on me
それは正論にならないけど
That might not be a sound argument, but...
祭囃子のそのあとで
After the festival music fades
高ぶったままの人 泣き出してしまいそうな人
Some are still excited, while others are about to cry
多分同じだろう でも言葉にしようものなら
It's probably the same thing, but if I try to put it into words
稚拙が極まれり
It's the height of clumsiness
最高だってシュガーソング、幸せってビターステップ
A 'best' Sugar Song, a 'happy' Bitter Step
死ねない理由をそこに映し出せ
Project the reasons why you can't die onto that
惜しがったって等速で明日は来ちゃうけど
Even if we regret it, tomorrow comes at a constant speed
脳内天気予報のアップデートは果たしたなら
But if you've updated the weather forecast in your head...
みんな見えてるよー！
I can see everyone!
みんな声出してー！
Everyone, let out your voices!
ヘイ！
Hey!
Someday 狂騒界息を潜めても
Someday, even if we hold our breath in this chaotic world
Someday 正論に意味がなくなっても
Someday, even if sound arguments lose their meaning
Feeling song & step 鳴らし続けることだけが
Feeling song & step; only continuing to ring out
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる、Q.E.D.！
Will be the proof that makes us who we are, Q.E.D.!
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
生きてく理由をそこに映し出せ
Project the reasons for living onto that
北北東は後退さ その距離が誇らしい
North-northeast is a regression, but I'm proud of that distance
世界中を驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep on surprising the whole world
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
It's so sweet and bitter, I feel like my head is spinning
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's keep the party going towards the south-southwest
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It'll be a night that surprises the whole world
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, reflecting in a chain reaction
Goes on 一難去ってまた一難
Goes on, one trouble after another
一難去ってまた一難
One trouble after another
はい、ということで二人目のゲスト、
Yes, and so, the second guest...
レオナちゃん！
Reona-chan!
獅子神レオナ
Shishigami Reona
ワイルド・ガオー！
Wild Gaooo!
サバンナから大好きなお歌を求めてやってきた、
Coming from the savannah in search of the songs I love,
Re:AcT所属のVアーティスト、獅子神レオナだよ！
The V-artist from Re:AcT, I'm Shishigami Reona!
はい、では、しがないミリオンです、こんにちは！
Yes, well, this is Shiganai Million, hello!
よかった、終わったあとに緊張することってあるんだね。
Good, I guess there are times when you get nervous after it's over.
ある、今、めちゃくちゃ...あんなにノリノリで歌ってたのに。
There are. Right now, I'm... even though I was singing so excitedly.
というわけでね、歌唱部、ね、久々、結構久々ではあるもんね、そらといったら。
And so, the singing part, right, it's been a while, quite a while, for Sora.
そうなんだよね、なんか前フェスとかではね、一緒に歌ったりしてたんだけど。
That's right. We used to sing together at festivals and things before.
その時にね、あぁいい声だなぁ、一緒に歌いたいなぁってずっと思ってて。
At that time, I thought, "Ah, what a great voice, I want to sing together," all the time.
えー、嬉しい！
Eh, I'm happy!
嬉しい、ありがとう。それでなんか、もし良ければ出てくれないかなっていうお話をしました。
I'm happy, thank you. And so, I asked if you'd like to appear, if it's okay.
ね、もう即効でオッケーしたよね。
Right, I said yes immediately.
本当、やったやったやった！
Really? Yay, yay, yay!
ね、ね、そう、これ、歌ってみたを出したんだよ、レオナちゃんが。
Right, right, yeah, this, Reona-chan put out a cover of this.
うんうん、そうそう。それがあまりにも良かったから一緒に歌いたいなって思って。
Yeah, yeah, right, right. It was so good that I wanted to sing it together.
それで選んだのは...ガチだから。
The reason I chose it... is because I'm serious.
もうまさか一緒にね、セッションできると思わなかったから。
I never thought we'd be able to have a session together.
いやー、もうさ、ハモっちゃった！
Wow, we even harmonized!
ね、ハモったね。本当に。元々私もハモ入れてたんだけど。
Right, we harmonized. Truly. I had originally put in harmonies myself.
めちゃくちゃハモできるから、なしにして！って言って。
But since we could harmonize so well, I said, "Let's do it without [the pre-recorded ones]!"
誕生日だったらもうブワーってやりたい！ってなって。
I felt like, "It's a birthday, so I want to go all out!"
コーラスに徹するので、サビは、今日の主役が歌ってくださいよ！ってなったんですよね。
I'll stick to the chorus, so please, today's star, you sing the chorus!
うん、そう。私もだから、ハモできたから、レオナちゃんがメインのところはやったんだけど。
Yeah, right. Me too, because I could harmonize, I did the parts where Reona-chan was the lead.
それ以外の場所を交互にやる？って言ったら、「いや、いい」って言われて。
When I asked if we should alternate the other parts, I was told, "No, it's fine."
意志を感じたの、自分の中で。「あ、確固たる意志がある」って。
I felt a strong will in myself. Like, "Ah, there's a firm resolution here."
「いや、絶対今日はメインだけを歌わせるぞ！」っていう。
"No, I'm definitely going to make you sing only the lead today!"
よかった、でも呼んでくれて。
I'm glad, though, that you called me.
いや、こちらこそ来てくれてめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったよ。本当に。
No, I was incredibly happy that you came. Really.
なんかステージもめっちゃ豪華でさ。でしょ？あれ、一個持って帰っても許されるの？
The stage is really grand, too. Right? Is it okay if I take one of those home with me?
何？何？ヌヌヌは増殖...上の、あ、下のでもいいよ。
What? What? Nununu is multiplying... the one on top, oh, even the one on the bottom is fine.
あ、この子たち？この子たちはね、増えるものだから持って帰っても大丈夫！
Ah, these guys? These guys, they multiply, so it's okay to take them home!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
待って、プレゼント渡すはずなのにプレゼントもらっちゃった！全然いい、間違えちゃった。
Wait, I was supposed to give you a gift, but I received one instead! It's totally fine, I made a mistake.
大事にしてあげてください、うちのヌヌヌを。大事にしちゃおうかな、やったー！
Please take good care of our Nununu. I think I will, yay!
ね、でも、もう時間っぽいんだよね。じゃあ、スクショ撮ろう！いいよ！
Right, but it seems like it's about time. Well then, let's take a screenshot! Sure!
イエーイ！たくさん撮って！イエーイ！
Yay! Take lots of them! Yay!
嬉しい、嬉しいわ。あ、でも、そろそろちょっと群れの移動にさ...
I'm happy, I'm so happy. Ah, but it's about time for the herd to move...
群れの移動もちょっと待ってもらってるから。そろそろ行かないといけないっぽいんだよね。
they're waiting for me to move with them. So it seems like I have to go soon.
大変な時に来てくれてありがとう。全然、ごめんね。いや、こちらこそ。
Thank you for coming at such a busy time. Not at all, sorry. No, same here.
でもね、このあと移動中に絶対ね、可愛い可愛いそらちゃんの新衣装絶対見るから！
But, while I'm moving after this, I'll definitely, definitely watch Sora-chan's cute new costume!
うん、もうじーっと見ながら歩く。じーっと見てて、危ない危ない。
Yeah, I'll walk while staring at it. Keep staring, wait, that's dangerous.
ダメだよね、群れに迷惑かかる. そうだよね. じゃあ、移動して止まって見ますからね、しっかり。
That's no good, it'll trouble the herd. Right. Then I'll move, stop, and watch, carefully.
皆さん、たくさんお祝いしてあげてくださいね！はい、ということで、改めておめでとう！
Everyone, please give her lots of celebratory wishes! Yes, so, once again, congratulations!
ありがとう！じゃあまたね！また遊ぼうね！バイバイ、ね、ね。
Thank you! Well then, see you later! Let's play again! Bye-bye, yeah, yeah.
もう二人もお祝いに来てくれちゃった、嬉しい、嬉しい！
Two people have already come to celebrate, I'm so happy!
やー、でも、次は、ここじゃなくて、ステージの真ん中で歌っちゃおうかな！
Yeah, but next, I think I'll sing not here, but in the middle of the stage!
みんな！今日はお誕生日放送見に来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you for coming to watch the birthday broadcast today!
嬉しいよ！
I'm so happy!
みんな楽しみにしててくれた？ありがとう、ありがとう！
Were you all looking forward to it? Thank you, thank you!
奥のみんなも見えてるよ！
I can see everyone in the back, too!
えへへ、えへへ。わー！
Hehehe, hehehe. Wah!
まだまだ続くから、このあとも楽しみにしててね！
There's still more to come, so please look forward to the rest!
Chu-Chu-Lu Chu-Lu-Tu-Tu-Tu
Chu-Chu-Lu
作詞・作曲・編曲：koman
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: koman
というわけで、さっきまでとはちょっと違うかもしれないけど、見て、新衣装なんですよ。
So, it might be a bit different from before, but look, it's a new costume.
あれ、それ、どう？
Hey, how is it?
...っていうことかな。
...I guess that's how it is.
でもみんな、最後まで見てね！
But everyone, please watch until the end!
Chu-chu-lu, chu-chu-lu, chu-chu-lu
男の子はいつでも
Boys are always
強がりな生き物
Creatures who try to act tough
弱さを嫌って
Hating their own weakness
涙は流さないよ
They don't shed tears
傷つかない人など
There's no such thing as someone
この世にいないから
Who never gets hurt in this world
たまには本当の
So every once in a while
声を聞かせてよ
Let me hear your true voice
あなたはまだ不器用な
You're still an angel
天使
Who can be quite clumsy
もういいよ気張らずに
It's alright, you don't have to strain yourself
捨てて
Just let it go
深く深く愛してよ
Love me deeply, so deeply
酸いも甘いもメモリア
Memories of both sour and sweet times
恋は怖くないんだよ
Love isn't something to be afraid of
あなたなら大丈夫
You'll be just fine
強く強く抱きしめてよ
Hold me tight, so very tight
あの夜にサヨナラを
Say goodbye to that night
私がここで待ってるよ
I'll be waiting right here
だからもっと
So, please, more than ever
恐れずに愛してね
Love me without any fear
Chu-chu-lu, chu-chu-lu, chu-chu-lu
誰もが一人だけじゃ
Everyone is a creature
いられない生き物
Who can't stay all by themselves
弱さを認め合い
They admit their weaknesses
助け合うものよ
And help each other out
私もまだ不器用な
I'm still an angel
天使
Who can be quite clumsy
お願いよ翼を
Please, spread your wings
広げて
Open wide
高く高く飛んでくよ
Flying high, so very high
目指すのはサンクチュアリ
Our destination is the sanctuary
二人だけの楽園で
In a paradise just for the two of us
甘い果実かじり
Biting into the sweet fruit
手をぎゅっと繋いでいて
Hold my hand tightly
じゃなきゃ離れちゃうよ
Or else we might drift apart
ずっとここで一緒だよ
We'll be here together forever
だからもっと
So, please, more than ever
いつまでも愛してね
Love me for all eternity
ハイ！ ハイ！
Hai! Hai!
いつかできた傷跡に
If my tears sting the scars
涙が沁みちゃうのなら
That were made some time ago
笑顔のバンドエイドを
Then I will give you
あげるから
A band-aid of smiles
前を向いて さあ行こう
Look forward, and let's go
深く深く愛してよ
Love me deeply, so deeply
何もかもがメモリア
Every single thing is a memory
恋は怖くないでしょ
Love isn't something to be afraid of, right?
あなたと私なら
If it's you and me together
強く強く抱きしめてよ
Hold me tight, so very tight
あの夜にサヨナラを
Say goodbye to that night
私がここで待ってるよ
I'll be waiting right here
だからもっと
So, please, more than ever
恐れずに愛してね
Love me without any fear
せーの！
Ready, go!
Chu-chu-lu, chu-chu-lu, chu-chu-lu
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to keep seeing the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
それぞれ違った心で
With our own individual hearts
走れ Go
Run on, go!
Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)
ホロライブ！
Hololive!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に目ん食らってた
Everywhere I looked, I was blinded by the darkness
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳は奪われた
But then my eyes were captured by a tiny glimmer of hope
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my heart, which was shaking with anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞ってみたよ
I tried to squeeze out every last bit of courage
諦める文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up," I move forward
苦しい時ももう私は一人じゃないから
Because even when things are tough, I'm not alone anymore
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
My heart won't stop racing
どこどこ超えてく 世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that goes beyond anywhere
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try and access it
後悔なんてさせない
I won't let you have any regrets
これこれ誓った心で走れゴー
With this heart that has made its vow, run and go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい思いは
These dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
Will deliver a light never seen before to the real world
いつも聞こえるエールはここにキャプチャして
Capturing all the cheers I always hear right here
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
It makes me want to search for a new light once again
君の笑顔を保存して進む
Saving your smiles as I move forward
悲しい時に見返すよ力が沸くから
I'll look back at them when I'm sad, because they give me strength
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams with pride
キセキのストーリー
A miraculous story
一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
Let's create an endless dream together
誰一人欠かせない
This world where love waits,
愛が待ったこの世界
where no one is left behind
これこれ誓った心で彩れ
Paint it with this heart that has made its vow
みんな、今日は一緒に見てくれてありがとう！お誕生日のお祝いも嬉しいよー！
Everyone, thank you for watching with me today! I'm so happy about the birthday wishes!
悲しい時も 寂しい時も
Whether it's sad times or lonely times
信じ合える思いがある
There are feelings we can believe in together
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
Without forgetting, I want to keep this heartbeat sounding out
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ
Overflowing into this endless world
笑顔たち
Our smiles
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way
時には涙してまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes crying, but wanting to laugh together again
どんな未来も見たい
I want to see whatever the future holds
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そうキセキの一歩を
Let's take that miraculous step forward
息切らして夢追いかけたい
Chasing my dreams even if I'm out of breath
ワクワク止まらない
My heart won't stop racing
どこどこ超えてく 世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that goes beyond anywhere
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try and access it
後悔なんてここにない
There are no regrets here
これこれ誓った心で作るわ
I'll create it with this heart that has made its vow
というわけで、シュシュっとShiny Smily Story、
And with that, I sang "Chu-Chu-Lu"
2曲続けて歌いました！
and "Shiny Smily Story" back-to-back!
まずはこちらの新衣装のお披露目になりますね。
First of all, it's time to reveal this new costume.
どうですか？
How do you like it?
ねえ、見て見て見て！これさ、
Hey, look, look, look! You see this?
まずこちらの衣装ではスカートに星がつくんですよ。
First, for this costume, there are stars on the skirt.
ねー、可愛いでしょ。
Right? It's cute, isn't it?
あと足ですね。
And then my legs.
足。このブーツ。
My legs. These boots.
こっち羽もあるブーツ。
These boots even have wings on them.
そして、こう、ふって上がってくると、こっち側が白系、
And then, as you move up... this side is white,
こっち側がピンク。
and this side is pink.
ねぇねぇ、ちょっとアシンメトリーだけど
See, it's slightly asymmetrical,
とっても可愛い感じ。
which I think is really cute.
全体的にね、ピンクですね。
It's pink all over.
そしてここの胸んとこリボンもありますし。
And there's a ribbon here on the chest, too.
なんとお耳にはあん肝がついていますよと。
And would you believe it, Ankimo is right here on my ear!
リボンもピンク！
The ribbon is pink, too!
全部ピンク！可愛いでしょ！
Everything is pink! Isn't it cute?
だからほら、
So, you see...
もちろんの桜とも...
And of course, with the cherry blossoms...
...相性がぴったり。
...it's a perfect match.
ね、見てこっちのステージもすごくない？
Hey, look, isn't this stage amazing too?
めちゃくちゃ可愛い！わあ！
It's super cute! Wow!
すごい！イエーイ！
Amazing! Yay!
さて、ここでポーズを決める私は...
Well then, as I strike a pose here...
みんなこれを撮って
Everyone, take photos of this
たくさんポストしてね！
and post them a lot!
なかなかね、普段の配信では聞き...気付...ずら...感じレベルですけど
It's a feeling you don't really get to... see... notice... in regular streams.
おっ！トレンドにしたの？
Oh! You got it trending?
みんなのおかげだ！ありがとう！ありがとう！ありがとう！
It's all thanks to everyone! Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
この衣装ではしゃぐなんて感じする？
Do I look like I'm frolicking in this outfit?
ごめんね、
I'm sorry,
いっぱいいっぱい呟いてありがとう！
thank you for tweeting so much!
今も言った通り、この後もいろいろあるから
As I just mentioned, there's still a lot more coming up,
まだ見てね！へへっ！
so keep watching! Hehe!
お水飲む
I'm drinking water
ときのそら お披露目誕生日 2024
Tokino Sora Debut Anniversary & Birthday 2024
美味しい
Tastes good
では、そろそろ次の曲に行きますか？
Well then, shall we move on to the next song soon?
次の曲聴いてください。
Please listen to the next song.
Grip!
そら先輩！
Sora-senpai!
ベ先輩！
Bae-senpai!
ベぇちゃんだよ！トキメキじゃ！
It's Bae-chan! With excitement!
制服じゃない... 誕生日おめでとう！
Not a uniform... Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Grip! ですから！
Because it's Grip!
Grip! だよ！
It's Grip!
頑張りますよ！
I'll do my best!
緊張しないで！
Don't be nervous!
藍色に散らばる 七つの星よ
Oh, seven stars scattered in the indigo sky
それぞれに今 想いは募り
Each of our feelings now grow stronger
打ち砕かれて 愛を叫んだ
Crushed and shouting out love
逃げ出すこともできずに
Without being able to run away
夢にすがりつく
Clinging to dreams
行儀ざまな日々などにはもう
To those unrefined days, I'll never...
負けない
...lose again
目覚めよ この瞬間を
Awaken, this moment
やがて僕らを取り巻くであろう
That will surely surround us soon
咽せ返るような リアルな日常
This choking, realistic everyday life
大切なものはなんだ
What is the thing that's precious?
贅沢な世界の中に
Inside this extravagant world
見え隠れする 永遠の欠片
Glimpses of fragments of eternity
手を伸ばして掴んで
Reach out your hand and grab it
僕らの今をきっちり歩いてこう
Let's walk through our 'now' properly
後悔はしないと
Saying I won't regret it
先へ進んだ
I moved forward
笑う門には福福
Good fortune comes to the gate of laughter
結局今もわからないけど
In the end, I still don't know
変わり始めた 未来に
In the future that has started to change
怯むことはない
There's no need to falter
それが人生の醍醐味という
That is the real pleasure of life...
ものでしょう
...I suppose
ギリギリで生きる 僕らの
We, living on the edge
確かな胎動が違学しても
Even if our certain destinies are different
思い込みでも強く粘えばいい
Even if it's just a belief, it's fine if it's strong
本物になれる日まで
Until the day we can become the real thing
冷酷な世界の中で
Inside this cold-hearted world
潰されそうな 愛情の芽吹き
The sprouting of love that seems about to be crushed
手を伸ばして掴んで
Reach out your hand and grab it
僕らの今にしっかり刻み込もう
Let's engrave it firmly into our 'now'
お、この音は？この音は？
Oh, this sound? This sound?
何ですかこの音は？
What is this sound?
この音何でしょうね？
I wonder what this sound is?
いくよ？ギター！
Here we go? Guitar!
目覚めよ この瞬間を
Awaken, this moment
やがて僕らを取り巻くであろう
That will surely surround us soon
光るよな Real な日常
A shining, real daily life
大切なものは何だ?
What is the most important thing?
贅沢な世界の中に
In this extravagant world
見え隠れする永遠の欠片
Are glimpses of eternal fragments
さわって つかんで
Touch it, grasp it
僕らの今をきっちり歩いてこう
Let's walk firmly through our "now"
最後には笑っちゃおう
In the end, let's just laugh
僕らの今をきっちり歩いてこう
Let's walk firmly through our "now"
そら先輩！
Sora-senpai!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
信じ合う仲間と一緒に
Together with friends who believe in each other
飛ばせ 拳を 突き上げよう
Let it fly, let's thrust our fists up
終わらない青春に
To an endless youth
青春アーカイブ
作詞・作曲・編曲：HoneyWorks
Seishun Archive
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: HoneyWorks
まずは深呼吸 落ち着いて Hey! みんなで揃えば 来るじゃんじゃん
First take a deep breath and calm down, Hey! When we're all together, it'll come, jan jan
光る 透き通る 声 合わせて
Let out a shining, clear voice in unison
青春 感じている もう 最高潮
Feeling youth, it's already the climax
成長した姿を見せたい
I want to show how much I've grown
リハは完璧 本番はもっと電撃で
The rehearsal was perfect, the real performance will be even more electric
大切な思い出 たくさんあるけどね まだ
There are many precious memories, but still
感傷に浸ってる暇はない
There's no time to indulge in sentimentality
今世紀最大の夏が始まる
The greatest summer of this century is beginning
想像の果てにある高み
The heights that lie beyond imagination
勝ち取った景色は尊い
The scenery we've won is precious
逃げるな 限界の壁超えて
Don't run away, cross the wall of limits
僕らはまだチャレンジャー
We are still challengers
冷たい声に溺れたって
Even if we drown in cold voices
かすかな望みをたぐり寄せるように
As if pulling in a faint hope
期待外れだと誰かが嘆く
Someone laments that it was a disappointment
痛いと痛いがいつも戦う
Pain and pain are always fighting
プライドだけを頼りに抗う 自分を信じたい
Resisting with only pride as a guide, I want to believe in myself
努力は報われる 笑いたい奴は笑ってな
Effort pays off, let those who want to laugh, laugh
感傷に浸ってる暇はない
There's no time to indulge in sentimentality
今世紀最大の夏が始まる
The greatest summer of this century is beginning
反響が足りない もっともっと
Not enough reverberation, more, more!
後悔はさせない
I won't let you regret it
想像の果てにある高み
The heights that lie beyond imagination
勝ち取った景色は尊い
The scenery we've won is precious
逃げるな 限界の壁超えて
Don't run away, cross the wall of limits
僕らはまだチャレンジャー
We are still challengers
お邪魔しまーす！
We're barging in!
そら先輩！
Sora-senpai!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
言っちゃいますけどさ
I'm just gonna say it
そうです先輩、可愛すぎて...
That's right senpai, you're too cute...
やっほー！
Yah-hoo!
結婚してください！
Please marry me!
求婚しちゃった！
I proposed!
乗らないか？
Won't you accept?
乗ってくれよ！
Please accept!
もう感謝しちゃった！
I'm just so grateful!
しかも今なんと私たち、トレンド2位ということで！
And right now, we are actually trending at number two!
やったー！ ありがとうー！
Yay! Thank you!
初めてかも、トレンド。
This might be the first time we've trended.
え、そうなの？
Oh, really?
おめでとう！ 誕生日おめでとう！
Congratulations! Happy Birthday!
いや、みんながね、こうやって盛り上げてくれるからだね。
Well, it's because everyone is getting excited like this.
ありがとう、ありがとう。みんなもありがとうね。
Thank you, thank you. Thank you to everyone as well.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
えー、そしてですね、Gripは、べーちゃんと歌ったんだけど。
And then, I sang "Grip" with Bae-chan.
ずっと一緒に歌いたいって言ってたんですよね。
We've always said we wanted to sing together, right?
そう、めっちゃ歌いたいって、デビュー当時からね、言ってたんですよね。
Yeah, we've been saying we really wanted to sing it since our debut.
はい、それを叶えたくて、呼んじゃいました。
Yes, I wanted to make that come true, so I invited her.
感動と、もう尊敬がもう、ありがとうございます！
The emotion and respect are just... thank you so much!
何、何、何！？ 大丈夫？ 土下座！？
What, what, what!? Are you okay? Prostrating!?
本当に楽しかったです。本当にありがとう。
It was really fun. Truly, thank you.
そして、まつりちゃんとこよりちゃん。
And then, Matsuri-chan and Koyori-chan.
やっぱ今回の衣装もアイドルって感じの衣装にしたんで。
This time's outfit too, I made it feel like an idol's outfit.
やっぱみんなでアイドルっぽい曲も歌いたいなと思って。
So I thought I wanted to sing an idol-like song with everyone.
この曲めっちゃ好きなのね。
I really love this song.
あのね、裏話するとね、あの、二人のほうがずっと練習して緊張してた。
To tell you a behind-the-scenes story, those two were practicing and nervous the whole time.
えー！ やだー！
No way! (Laughter)
でもまあ、ゲストパート生のものって結構珍しいんで。
But well, it's quite rare to have a live guest part like this.
ちょっと緊張感がね、あったよね。
There was a bit of tension, wasn't there?
自分のはさ、いいんですけど、頑張んなきゃみたいな。
My own parts are fine, but it's like, "I have to do my best!"
いやいや、全然、ありがとうございました。
No, no, not at all, thank you very much.
みんな草って言ってますね、ありがとうございます。
Everyone is saying "Lol" (kusa). Thank you.
おい、なんで草って書いて帰ってって！
Hey, why are you writing "kusa" and leaving!?
いや、そんな感じで、やっぱりね、ホロのメンバーとも一緒に...
Well, in that way, after all, with Hololive members together...
でも私はさ、なんか生放送にこだわりすぎちゃってるから...
But I'm, you know, a bit too particular about live broadcasting...
いやいや、いいことだ、いいことだ。
No, no, it's a good thing, a good thing.
そうだからね、今日はね、みんながね、こうスケジュールを合わせて来てくれたわけだよ。
So today, everyone adjusted their schedules to come here.
本当にありがとうございます。
Truly, thank you very much.
当然ですよ！ 当たり前だよ！ おめでとう！ むしろありがとうございます！
Of course! Naturally! Congratulations! Rather, thank you!
みんなでスクショも撮っちゃお。
Let's take a screenshot together.
やったー！
Yay!
えーとな、どんなポーズ？
Well, what kind of pose?
どうする？
What should we do?
きゅんきゅん、きゅんみたいな。
Something like "Kyun kyun, kyun."
べーちゃんだけなんかピースして遠くにいるけど。
Only Bae-chan is doing a peace sign far away though.
なんで、なんで？
Why, why?
混ざっちゃったオタクみたいになってるけど。
She's like an otaku who just mixed in.
いや、そら先輩は前、大丈夫。
No, Sora-senpai is in front, so it's fine.
ありがとうございます。私たち、ホロライブだよ！
Thank you very much. We are Hololive!
ホロライブポーズ？ これがホロライブポーズ？
Hololive pose? Is this the Hololive pose?
ホロライブサンク... しゃ！
Hololive thank... you!
ちょっと、なんか違う。なんかサンク。
Wait, something is a bit different. Something is "thank."
なんで面白くなっちゃうんだろう。ごめん、そらのせいかもしれない。
Why does it end up being funny? Sorry, it might be my fault.
え、これ、だってもう、こうじゃない？
Wait, but isn't it like this? Like this!
こうなっちゃうから。違う、それは違う、色々違う。
It ends up like this. No, that's wrong, various things are wrong.
やってた！
I was doing it!
わーい！ さん、はい！
Yay! One, two!
いやでもね、こんな風にわいわいやることが本当に久しぶりなので。
But well, doing things noisily like this is really after a long time.
とっても嬉しい。本当に来てくれてありがとう。
I'm very happy. Truly, thank you for coming.
えー、いいの、いいの。いいの、いいの。ありがとう！
No, no, it's fine! Good, good! Thank you!
べーちゃんもありがとう。
Bae-chan, thank you too.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
めっちゃ喜んじゃう。嬉しい、嬉しい。
I'm so happy. I'm glad, I'm glad.
なんか、もらってばっかりだな。
I feel like I'm only receiving things.
いやいやいや、そんなことないのに。
No, no, no, that's not true at all.
はい、OKで。はい。
Alright, okay. Yes.
もう、なんと、ゲストパートが終わる時間です！
Now, believe it or not, it's time for the guest part to end!
やだー！ やだー！ ここに住むー！
No! No! I want to live here!
床になる。ずるずる。はい、持って帰りますよ、みんなが。
Becoming the floor. Slithering. Alright, I'll take them home.
やだー！ やだー！ まって！
No! No! Wait!
ちょっと重いな。ちょっと重いな。
A bit heavy. A bit heavy.
なんでー！ 祭りが踏んであげるよ。いいです。
Why!? Matsuri will step on you. No thanks.
なんか、いいです。
I'm good.
はい、というわけで、今日は来てくれて本当にありがとうございました。
Alright, so thank you very much for coming today.
こちらこそ！ ありがとう！ おめでとう！
Likewise! Thank you! Congratulations!
この後も楽しんでね！
Please enjoy the rest as well!
はーい！ ありがとうー！ バイバイ！
Okay! Thank you! Bye bye!
いやー、賑やかなメンバーで、嬉しかったな。
Wow, I was happy to be with such a noisy group of members.
それじゃあ、次は、またあっちのステージに戻って、歌おうかな。
Well then, next, I'll go back to that stage and sing.
何があるかな。
I wonder what's next.
みんなはどうかな？ 可愛いかな？
How is it, everyone? Is it cute?
「おー」って言ってくれてありがとう。
Thank you for saying "Oh!"
ちょっとお姉さんって感じで、決めちゃってるんだけど、似合ってるかな？
I'm looking a bit like an older sister, but does it suit me?
この格好でも歌っていくから...
I'll be singing in this outfit too...
この後も見てね！ うわーい！
...so please watch the rest too! Whoo!
アイドル
Idol
But that girl up there is a lot of mania
知りたいその秘密ミステリア
I want to know that secret, a mysteria
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even being ditzy is her domain
完璧だね...
It's perfect, isn't it...
…嘘つきな君は
...you, the liar,
天才的なアイドル様
are a genius idol.
アイドル
作詞・作曲：Ayase
Idol
Lyrics & Composition: Ayase
今日何食べた？好きな本は？
What did you eat today? What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
Where do you go when you go out to play?
何も食べてない それは内緒
I haven't eaten anything. That's a secret.
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
No matter what you're asked, you're elusive.
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So nonchalant, yet so brilliant.
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
A secret just out of reach tastes like honey.
あれもないないない
That's not there, not there, not there.
これもないないない
This is not there, not there, not there.
好きなタイプは？ 相手は？ さあ答えて
What's your type? Who is it? Come on, answer me.
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ」
"I don't really know what it's like to fall in love."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Whether it's a lie or the truth, I'll never know.
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
With those words, another person falls for you.
また好きにさせる
You make them love you again.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone's eyes are drawn to you.
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You are the perfect and ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
You'll never appear again.
一番星の生まれ変わり
The reincarnation of the first star.
あ、その笑顔で愛してるで
Ah, with that smile, saying "I love you,"
誰も彼も虜にしていく
you captivate everyone.
その瞳が その言葉が
Those eyes, those words,
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if they're lies, it's perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special.
我々は端からおまけです
We're just extras from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're the background character B to the star.
全てがあの子のおかげなわけない
Everything can't be thanks to her.
洒落臭い 妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
It's irritating. There's no way there isn't envy and jealousy.
これはネタじゃない からこそ許せない
This isn't a joke. That's why I can't forgive it.
完璧じゃない 君じゃ許せない
You're not perfect. I can't forgive you.
自分を許せない 誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I can't forgive myself. I won't acknowledge anyone but you, who are stronger than anyone.
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes in and worships you.
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
The truly strongest and invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses can be found.
一番星を宿している
You harbor the first star.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
Don't show your weak side, no, no.
知りたくないとこは見せずに
Without showing the parts they don't want to know.
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
I hate it if you're not one of a kind.
それこそ本物のアイ
That is true love.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Rousing the media with your specialty smile.
隠し切るこの秘密だけは
Only this secret will be hidden completely.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
A career built on the lie of "I love you."
これこそ私なりの愛だ
This is my own kind of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
The sweat that flows is beautiful aqua.
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
These eyelids that hide rubies.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing, dancing, and performing, I am Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the ultimate love.
誰かに愛されたことも
The fact that I've never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したことも
or loved anyone either.
ないそんな私の嘘が
I believe that one day my lies
いつか本当になること
will become the truth.
信じてる
I believe it.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
One day I'll surely have it all.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I am such a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのこと
Because I want to love everyone
ちゃんと愛したいから
just as I am.
今日も嘘をつくの
I'll tell lies again today.
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
Hoping that these words will one day become true.
それでもまだ
Even so, I still
君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
couldn't say it to you and you.
あ、やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it.
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely not a lie.
愛してる
I love you.
パレ・パレ・パレ
作詞・作曲：堀江晶太
Pare Pare Pare
Lyrics & Composition: Shota Horie
パレ・パレ・パレ 輝くんだよ
Pare, pare, pare, it's going to shine.
呼び合う声を合図に
With the voices calling each other as a signal.
パレ・パレ・パレ 探しに行く
Pare, pare, pare, I'm going to look for it.
スターとは何だったって
What a star was.
イエーイ！二つ目の衣装はこれだー！
Yay! My second outfit is this!
ジャケット！ワーイ！
A jacket! Yay!
タラー！
Ta-da!
独り言 綴った
I wrote down my soliloquy.
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I just ran because I wanted things to start.
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Far away, it lit up in the darkness.
それは 眩しすぎた名前
That was a name that was too bright.
それは 優しすぎる思い出
Those were memories that were too kind.
もっと 近づけと手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer.
思いがけず結びあった
Unexpectedly tied together,
ほら 今 迷走は 僕らになった
Look, now the straying has become us
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-Pare-Pare, shine bright!
悔しさも愛おしさも連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your affection with you
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings - you can take flight
ささやかな祈りばっか光 終わりなき兆し
With only humble prayers shining, an endless sign
君と見つけたこと胸を張れるよ
I can be proud of what I found with you
ここからこれから Oui Bright Parade Forever
From here, from now on, Oui Bright Parade Forever
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
まだ 頼りない予感を
Still, this unreliable premonition
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing it, there's nothing to be ashamed of
誰も解けないおまじない
A spell that no one can break
いつか また会えるおまじない
A spell to meet again someday
あの日ゼロに始まったストーリー
A story that started from zero that day
数えきれないことの端 数えるような思いじゃないさ
The fragments of countless things aren't thoughts to be counted
ほら 今 僕らを一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call us one
パレパレパレ 美しいんだよ
Pare-Pare-Pare, it's beautiful!
許しあえる切な 夜はきらめく
The painful moments of mutual forgiveness, the night sparkles
雨 晴れ 風 混ざり合う空
Rain, shine, wind - the blending sky
ふさわしい道とは 君と歩くことさ
The right path is the one I walk with you
ただいまを聞けば おかえりって叫ぶよ
When I hear "I'm home," I'll shout "Welcome back"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that natural?
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-Pare-Pare, shine bright!
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
Filling the darkness are you and I
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-Pare-Pare, shine bright!
悔しさも愛おしさも連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your affection with you
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings - you can take flight
ささやかな祈りばっか光 終わりなき兆し
With only humble prayers shining, an endless sign
君と飛び込んでいく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in with you, it's a wonderful start
ここからこれから Oui Bright Parade Forever
From here, from now on, Oui Bright Parade Forever
はい！というわけで...
Yes! And so...
『Oui Bright Parade』アイドルver.でした！
That was "Oui Bright Parade" Idol ver.!
ステージジャケットのお衣装、2つ目ですね。
This is the second outfit, the stage jacket.
1つ目、2つ目と来たら...
If we've had the first and the second...
わー！というわけで、えー、みんな見てくださいよ！ジャケット可愛いでしょう！
Wow! Anyway, everyone, look! The jacket is cute, right?
ちょっとさ、同じ衣装なんだけど、
You know, even though it's the same outfit,
上着があるだけでさ、全然違うイメージになるよね！
just having a jacket makes it look totally different!
すごいさ、なんか一気にいっぱい貰った感じがして、ドキドキしちゃう！えへへ。
I feel like I've gotten so much at once, it's making my heart race! Ehehe.
みんな、これもたくさんお祝いしてね！
Everyone, celebrate this outfit a lot too!
はい、というわけで、えー、ここで、
Alright, so, right now,
みんな待ってたかな？グッズもあるよー！
was everyone waiting? We have merchandise too!
それも見ていこう！ポン！
Let's check it out! Bang!
誕生日記念2024
誕生日記念フルセット
◇グッズ4種
・「アイドルそらちゃん」ラバーマット
・そらとも証明書
・そらともIDカードホルダー
・一緒におでかけそらちゃんぬいぐるみ ピンクパーカー衣装ver.
◇ボイス2種
誕生日記念フルセット 購入特典
直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード
Birthday Celebration 2024
Birthday Celebration Full Set
◇4 Types of Merch
- "Idol Sora-chan" Rubber Mat
- Soratomo Certificate
- Soratomo ID Card Holder
- Go Out Together Sora-chan Plushie (Pink Hoodie Outfit Ver.)
◇2 Types of Voices
Birthday Celebration Full Set Purchase Bonus
Hand-signed & Message-included polaroid-style bromide card
今年も、あります！グッズ！
This year, we have them again! Merch!
誕生日記念2024、誕生日記念フルセット！
Birthday Celebration 2024, Birthday Celebration Full Set!
グッズ4種、「アイドルそらちゃん」ラバーマット、
Four types of merch: "Idol Sora-chan" rubber mat,
そらとも証明書、そらともIDカードホルダー、
Soratomo certificate, Soratomo ID card holder,
一緒におでかけそらちゃんぬいぐるみ、ピンクパーカー衣装ver.、
Go Out Together Sora-chan Plushie (Pink Hoodie Outfit Ver.),
ボイス2種類！そして、
two types of voices! And,
こちらのフルセットの方の購入特典は、直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード！
the purchase bonus for this full set is a hand-signed and message-included polaroid-style bromide card!
1枚1枚書きます！
I'll sign each and every one!
ぜひ、みなさん、ゲットしてね！
Please, everyone, go get them!
というわけで詳しく見ていきましょうか。
So, let's take a closer look at each item.
こちら！
Here it is!
「アイドルそらちゃん」ラバーマット
イラスト：おるだん
サイズ：約H34×W60cm
素材：ポリエステル・天然ゴム
"Idol Sora-chan" Rubber Mat
Illustration: Ordan
Size: Approx. H34 x W60cm
Material: Polyester, Natural rubber
ここか。えへへ。
Is it here? Ehehe.
まず1つ目！「アイドルそらちゃん」ラバーマット！
First, the first item! The "Idol Sora-chan" rubber mat!
おるだん先生が描いてくれたラバーマットですよ！
It's a rubber mat illustrated by Ordan-sensei!
これ、めちゃくちゃ可愛いし、誕生日の時しかゲットできないから、
This is super cute, and you can only get it during my birthday,
みんなこれを使ってパソコンの作業とかもウキウキになってくれると、
so if everyone uses this to make their computer work or whatever exciting,
とっても嬉しいです！
I'd be very happy!
可愛いよね、これ！
Isn't this cute?!
逆か。
Wait, is it backwards?
こんな感じです。
It looks like this.
そして続いてはこちら。
And next up is this.
そらとも証明書！
The Soratomo Certificate!
ということで。なんか、証明書みたいなものが私は出したことがなかったなと思って。
I realized I'd never released
anything like a certificate before.
めちゃめちゃ可愛い証明書。
It's a really cute certificate.
あと、メッセージも書きました！
I also wrote a message on it!
見えるかどうかはわからないけど、これを持ってるみんなは全員そらともだよ！
I don't know if you can see it,
but everyone who has this is a Soratomo!
ということで、ぜひゲットしてね。
So please be sure to get one.
そして次はこちら。
And next is this.
そらともIDカードホルダー。
The Soratomo ID Card Holder.
こちら、シンプルなものになってますね。ちょっと可愛い系なんですけど。
This has a simple design.
It's a bit on the cute side.
IDカードホルダーなので、いつでも付けられるようなシンプルなもの。
Since it's an ID card holder, it's
simple enough to wear anytime.
そしてね、例えば私はよく特典会とかやることがあるんですけど、
And, for example, I often
hold bonus events and such...
そういうときにはここに証明書を入れてきてもらえれば、
If you put your certificate in here for those,
「あ、本当そらともさんだ！」ってすぐに見つけることもできますね。
I'll be able to spot you right
away as a true Soratomo.
会社に使う人、学校で使う人、いっぱいいると思います。ぜひゲットしてください！
Whether for work or school,
I think many will use it. Please get one!
そして次はこちら。
And next is this.
え、これめっちゃ嬉しかったの！
Oh, I was so happy about this!
一緒におでかけそらちゃんぬいぐるみ ピンクパーカー衣装ver.
The "Going Out Together Sora-chan
Plushie: Pink Hoodie Outfit Ver."
ということで。ね、みんなさ、サムネのやつがさ、何でこんなちびっこじゃんってなってたから分かった？
Remember how everyone asked why I
looked so tiny in the thumbnail? See?
これ、見て。全く同じでしょ。
Look at this. It's exactly the same.
可愛いでしょ！ということで。
Cute, right?!
こちらね、帽子を付けたり外したりもできますし、
The hood can be put on or taken off,
チェーンがあるので、普通にそのままカバンとかにも付けられる。
And it has a chain, so you can
just attach it to your bag.
そんなに大きくないサイズだから、
It's not that big of a size,
普段大きいの持ち歩くのは緊張しちゃうっていう子でも、
So even if you're shy about carrying
a big one around normally,
ぜひ、つけて私と一緒にお出かけしてね！
Please attach it and go out with me!
そして続いてはこちら。
And next up is this.
今回はシチュエーションボイスを2つご用意しました。
This time, we have two situation
voices prepared for you.
シチュエーションボイス「ライブ前に君と」。
Situation Voice: "With You Before the Live."
そしてシチュエーションボイス「一緒にお出かけ」。
And Situation Voice: "Going Out Together."
ということで、一緒にお出かけしたり、ライブ前に君と喋ったり、そんなシチュエーションで楽しんでください。
Please enjoy these scenarios, like going
out together or talking before a live.
そして次はこちら。
And next is this.
フルセット購入特典として、おるだん先生の描いてくださったチェキ風ブロマイドカードですね。
As a full set purchase bonus, we have a
polaroid-style bromide card by Ordan-sensei.
こちらにメッセージ入りで、全部書かせていただきます。
I will be hand-writing messages on all of these.
ぜひみんな、たくさんたくさんみんなのために書きたいから。
I really want to write lots
and lots of them for everyone.
いっぱい、いっぱい待ってるよ！
I'm waiting for lots and lots of you!
そして続いてはこちら。
And next up is this.
誕生日フルセットの詳細ですね。
Here are the details for the Birthday Full Set.
こちら、ラバーマット、証明書、IDカードホルダー、ぬいぐるみキーホルダー、ボイス2種類、
The mat, certificate, ID holder,
plushie, and two types of voices...
そしてそこにサインを書いたもの、私がサインを書いたものを皆さんにお届けできたらいいなと思っております。
Plus the signed item—the one I personally
signed—I hope to get those to all of you.
21時頃...過ぎてる！
Around 9 PM... It's already past!
過ぎてる！
It's past!
けど、販売をスタートします。
But sales are now starting.
よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
過ぎちゃったよ。わあ。
It's already past. Whoops!
というわけで、まあね。ここでお披露目そのものは最後なんですけど、
So, that's all for the reveals here.
このあと最後に、お知らせもあるからね。見てね。
But there's an announcement at
the very end, so stay tuned.
で、そのあと「メン限」の方でも、
And after that, on the membership stream,
なんかちょっと、もうちょっとお披露目あるかもね？
There might be a few more reveals?
「メン限」の人は先に見れちゃうぞ。
Members will get to see them first!
というわけで、ぜひ見に来てください！
So please come and watch!
それでは最後の曲行きましょう。
Now, let's head to the final song.
「誇り高きアイドル」。
Hokoritakaki Idol.
私のこと知ってますか？
Do you know about me?
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな
I wonder how my singing is.
うまく歌えてますか？
Am I singing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか
The outfit, the makeup...
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute?
振り付けとかファンサだとか
The choreography, the fan service...
喜んでもらえますか？
Do you enjoy them?
手は冷たくなって
My hands grow cold,
足は震える
And my legs tremble.
それでも歌いたい
But even so, I want to sing
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol.
馬鹿にする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of me.
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon.
アイドルなんていう言葉を
Don't use the word "idol"
見て不快な癖に言うな
If just looking at it makes you uncomfortable.
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't say hard work is to be expected.
イメージだとか強制するな
Don't force your image on me.
アイドルなんていう言葉は
The word "idol" is
この世で一番大嫌いだ
The thing I hate most in this world.
プライベート見えないから 分からないと思います
You can't see my private life, so I don't think you know,
性格とか悪い方です 騙しちゃっていますか？
but my personality is actually on the bad side. Am I deceiving you?
でも本気です 本気なんです ありのままの私を
But I'm serious, I'm really serious. Please take me as I am,
好きになって堕ちてください それって我儘ですか？
and come to love and fall for me. Is that too selfish?
「きもっ」とか言いたくない 全部わかってる
I don't want to say things like "gross." I know everything.
それでも好かれたい アイドルだから
Even so, I want to be liked. Because I'm an idol.
見にくい奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who are unsightly.
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate those who only make excuses.
こんなもんかという言葉を
The words "Is this all?"
軽々しく口にするな
Don't let them escape your lips so lightly.
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't decide the limits on your own.
笑い物になんてするな
Don't make me into a laughingstock.
アイドルなんていう言葉は
The word "idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
is what I hate most in this world.
向かい風を切り裂け
Cut through the headwind.
誇り高きアイドル
The proud idol.
目指そうぜ
Let's aim for it.
応援がなければ活動できない
I can't be active without your support.
好きなことばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
I can't live just by doing only what I like.
元気あげるはずがもらってばかりだし
I should be giving energy, but I'm only receiving it,
恩返しできる日まで待ってて
so please wait until the day I can repay the favor.
歓声が減っても 飽きられちゃっても
Even if the cheers decrease, even if people get tired of me,
それでも笑っていたい アイドルだから
even so, I want to keep smiling. Because I'm an idol.
ファンの愛があって
With the fans' love,
スタッフさんの愛があって
with the staff's love,
いつも家族の愛があって生きてる アイドル
and always with the family's love, I live. Idol.
馬鹿にする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of me.
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon.
アイドルなんていう言葉を
The word "idol"...
見てもいないくせに言うな
don't say it when you haven't even seen it.
甘いもんだと言うな
Don't say it's something sweet and easy.
イメージとか強要するな
Don't try to force your image on me.
アイドルなんていう言葉は
The word "idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
is what I hate most in this world.
みんな！今日は見に来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thanks for coming to see me today!
大好きだよ！
I love you!
はい、この後は22時からファンクラブでリハーサル映像公開があります！
Yes, after this from 22:00, the rehearsal video will be released on the fan club!
皆さん、え、可愛いシーン集ということでぜひ見てください！
Everyone, um, it's a collection of cute scenes, so please watch it!
そして、え、その次の日、5月の16日21時からファンクラブの方で感想配信がありまして、
And then, um, the next day, May 16th from 21:00, there will be an impressions livestream on the fan club,
新衣装のラフ画公開、おるだん先生からのメッセージ、
revealing the rough sketches for the new outfit and a message from Ordan-sensei.
16日21時から、え、ときのそらファンクラブの方で生配信するので、みんな一緒に見ていきましょうね！
It'll be live-streamed on Tokino Sora's fan club from the 16th at 21:00, so let's all watch it together!
そして、こちら！なんと1曲目に歌いました「STILL TIME」がですね、
And this! The song "STILL TIME" that I sang first...
今日の0時、24時に配信、デジタル配信が決定しております！
is scheduled for digital release at 0:00, 24:00 today!
そして同じく0時にMVがプレミア公開もされますので、
And the MV will also have its premiere at 0:00,
ぜひぜひこちらの方もお楽しみに！
so please look forward to this as well!
そして、メン限でも何かちょっとしたものがあるかもね！
And there might be something small for members too!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!